# ISAIAH FRANCOIS

# FULL STACK ENGINEER

- francoiscoding.com
- **\** 3529893703
- **♀** Clermont, Fl
- in francoiscoding
- FrancoisCoding

A software development and performance engineering expert with 2+ years of experience in developing quality assured applications and supervising/training students. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the hardware and software sides of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

## **Skills**

# PROGRAMMING TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

Python

C#

ReactJS

Express

Git

SQL

Redux

SASS

MongoDB

Cypress Testing

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Technical Troubleshooting and Debugging

Software and Engineering Documentation

Systems Architecture and Operations

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Performance Engineering

# **Projects**

#### CoachMe Health

Patient first non-profit organization dedicated to improving the health of low-income Americans with diabetes and heart disease with health coaching for those who need it most. Worked with a team to create an application to provide to the customers of clients.

ReactJS | Redux | SASS | Twillio | Cron Jobs | ChartJS | Cypress

- Collaborated remotely with a team of 7 Web Developers, and 2 UX/UI Designers to build a fully functional web application over the course of 8 weeks.
- Utilized Twilio's API alongside Cron Jobs to schedule messages to be sent to clients on the backend (Node.is) in order to communicate with users efficiently.

#### React Movies

An IMDB style real world Web Application in ReactJS. This application was built individually by me and serves to provide up to date movie infomation/details.

#### ReactJS | Bootstrap

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view information of over 10,000 of the latest movies released.
- Utilized The Movie Database API in order to display all information about latest movie titles to users.

#### Francois Games

A gaming platform where users can view up to date information on the latest games. This application was built individually by me and serves to provide up to date game infomation/details.

ReactJS | Bootstrap | Material UI | Styled-Components

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view over 300,000 game titles.
- Utilized the RAWG Video Games Database API in order to display all information about latest video game titles to users.

# **Employment**

## Lambda School

Team Lead

https://lambdaschool.com/ Nov. 2019 to Current

• Mentored 10+ students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems. Provided daily feedback and issue resolution of all curriculum through Slack interface. Led daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material. Delivered one-on-one feedback and code review on a weekly basis, giving feedback on areas of improvement.

## CoachMe Health

Full Stack Engineer

https://www.coachmehealth.org/ Oct. 2019 to Dec. 2019

• Developed and maintained system design documents (e.g. proofs of concept, requirements specification, subsystems) and collaborated with project managers to scope milestones, resource use, and report to clients (e.g. Patients) on project progress. Collaborated cross-functionally with clients and hardware engineers during the development and integration project phases to troubleshoot and/or debug software stacks. Converted requirements from clients into production ready APIs that enabled customization and streamlined work progress. Interfaced with development engineers to develop test cases, diagnose problems, and develop debugging methodologies.

# **Education**

Full Stack Web Development, Lambda School · May 2019 to Feb. 2020